<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github on Miro&#39;s World</title>
    <link>https://miroadamy.com/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github on Miro&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 13:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miroadamy.com/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to mirror Github and Bitbucket repositories</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2021-02-17-mirroring-repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2021-02-17-mirroring-repos/</guid>
      <description>Mirroring large number of GitHub or Bitbucket repositories Use case:
I want to create local clone of a large number of repositories from an organization in GitHub / Bitbucket.
Assumptions  user has SSH key registered with the GH / BB - can clone using ssh protocol user has successfully cloned at least one repo from command line before (the /etc/hosts contains host entries for BB and GH) user has modern version of Python 3 installed (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to list Github repositories and users</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2021-02-16-github-list-repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2021-02-16-github-list-repos/</guid>
      <description>How to list repositories in GitHub Use Case:
I want to maintain repositories in an organization in GitHub. To make sure I do not miss newly added ones, I want to use API access to retrieve the list of repositories in the organization.
Setup GitHub requires a token to access the API. This token is stored in an environment variable github_token and can be generated in the user profile section - settings - developer settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Hugo as well on GitLab pages</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2019-11-23-gitlab-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 22:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2019-11-23-gitlab-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Parallel building challenges Unlike Github, Gitlab considers Hugo blogs first class citizens and does not impose any restrictions on repo naming.
I had 3 challenges to overcome related to co-existence of GH and GL versions:
 I need to use same repo for both GH and GL the submodule link for public does not work on GL the site root is different - I have no custom domain forward for GitLab  Using same repo To separate the GH and GL, I have added 2 remotes to repo and special branch gitlab-pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub identity mixup</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2012-04-15-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2012-04-15-github/</guid>
      <description>After I created the ThinkWrap GitHub account and uploaded the public key, this key got somehow bound to GitHub identity &amp;lsquo;madamy&amp;rsquo;
I had to add user madamy to my public GitHub repo - where I keep the dot-files - https://github.com/radegast/dotvim
This may be an issue for people that have their own private accounts - the key management is the key.
This article is useful:
 http://sealedabstract.com/code/github-ssh-with-multiple-identities-the-slightly-more-definitive-guide/ http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/tools-and-tips/how-to-work-with-github-and-multiple-accounts/  Alternative Use https for forking , instead read/write ssh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
