<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>events on Miro&#39;s World</title>
    <link>https://miroadamy.com/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in events on Miro&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:22:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://miroadamy.com/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>All Day DevOps 2019</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2019-11-07-all-day-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2019-11-07-all-day-devops/</guid>
      <description>All Day DevOps 2019 - Notes I have attended the All Day Devops - https://www.alldaydevops.com/ on 06 Nov 2019 - an event that runs for 24 hours and has multiple tracks of content organized in 4 blocks.
The tracks:
 Keynotes Cultural Change DevSecOps SRE CI/CD Everything Cloud  The complete list is here: https://www.alldaydevops.com/2019-live-schedule - the play button points to the block video.
The Video URLs Channel 1  https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DockerCon 2018 - great event (with a small fly in the ointment)</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2018-12-07-dockercon-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 12:57:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2018-12-07-dockercon-2018/</guid>
      <description>I have just returned from DockerCon Europe 2018 and I’d like to share my impressions while they are fresh in my mind. It was my first DockerCon so I was not quite sure what to expect. As the title says, it was great experience and barring the scaling issue (more below) could have been really awesome experience.
But let&amp;rsquo;s take things in order. First location - Barcelona. Hard to pick better place in December than Spain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for a new day (continued)</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-13-ready-for-a-new-day-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2006 22:05:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-13-ready-for-a-new-day-continued/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned yesterday, my expectations regarding Office 2007 were fairly low. I am not a big fan of office application suites and for most of my editing I am using either on-line tools (like Google docs or Writeboard) or Open Office. True, neither of them has the smoothness and fine polish of Microsoft Office 2003, neither has all of it&#39;s features, but - let&#39;s face it - I barely use maybe 10-20% of Word or Excel capabilities anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for a new day - or Vista-Office-Exchange launch</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-12-ready-for-a-new-day-or-vista-office-exchange-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 23:56:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-12-ready-for-a-new-day-or-vista-office-exchange-launch/</guid>
      <description>Today was a big day in Ottawa Microsoft community. The Congress Centre was hosting large event - simultaneous launch of Windows Vista, Office 2007 and Exchange server 2007. Because I have almost registered about two months ago, I attended the event. The &#34;almost&#34; means that I tried to register right after receiving MSDN Flash email, but many people must have been faster - I was put on waiting list on two of the 3 tracks (Developers and IT Pros) and before I could even try to register for the third track (Business), everything crashed, Web site hang and I have never heard back from them, nor received any email.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>