<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gadgets on Miro&#39;s World</title>
    <link>https://miroadamy.com/tags/gadgets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gadgets on Miro&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2007 23:51:23 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miroadamy.com/tags/gadgets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>iPod touch - first impressions</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-10-11-ipod-touch-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2007 23:51:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-10-11-ipod-touch-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>No, I have not bought it yet, to big disappointment of Gabo and Shane - sorry guys. I wanted to buy it but all FutureShop stores in Ottawa are hopelessly sold out and on-line delivery is 7-10 business days - which I hope I will beat if these guys get new shipment (maybe tomorrow ?).
I played with two demo pieces though for about 30 minutes, and here are the first impressions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on Sony Reader</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-01-27-more-on-sony-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2007 20:24:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-01-27-more-on-sony-reader/</guid>
      <description>I have been living with my Sony eReader for almost a month now and managed to read about two full books. If not the time crush in biometric project, I would have probably read much more than just two books - nevertheless, I do have some real life experience with the device.
First - the claimed battery life of 7500 page turns is BS. I have observed real battery life about 15-20 hours, so unless you manage to turn about 500 pages per hour, it just does not add up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got the Sony reader :-)</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-24-got-the-sony-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2006 11:24:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-24-got-the-sony-reader/</guid>
      <description>Despite Sony&#39;s attempt to ignore non-US markets and leave Canadians in the cold (pun intended, even if it is still above zero), I have become a proud owner of the wonderful gadget for all eBooks fans. I still do not have it physically, so I cannot put it under the tree. It is coming next week, when my friend who now enjoys the vacation down in the south returns. He was not only very kind to buy one for me too, but he also wrote a wonderfull review which he is going to post on the Net.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
