<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>europe on Miro&#39;s World</title>
    <link>https://miroadamy.com/tags/europe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in europe on Miro&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 11:22:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://miroadamy.com/tags/europe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe 2007 - 1</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-1/</guid>
      <description>Europe 2007 - 1: Switzerland, Lower Engadin The flight went pretty quickly. It was less than 7 hours, anyway. We crossed the night and the Atlantic in a short time and landed at 6 AM in rainy, wet Zurich.
The car I have retrieved from Europa car was Spanish Volkswagen make – Seat Leon. According the specification, it was a “medium size car”. And it maybe was, for European circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe 2007 - 2</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-2/</guid>
      <description>Europe 2007 - 2: Südtirol and Verona Welcome to Italy: Verona After the breakfast, we took off from Scuol direction Martina, via brief drive through Austria to Italy. If I would not consult the map, I would barely noticed the border crossing, because there was no passport control on neither of the Switzerland-Austria or Austria-Italy border. You will not really notice that you have left Switzerland either, unless you notice the prices on gas stations being suddenly in Euro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe 2007 - 3</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-3/</guid>
      <description>Europe 2007 - 3: Pisa, Tirrenia and Firenze Pisa and Firenze After wonderful evening in Verona, the next day after a very good breakfast (they even had whole-wheat breads), we spend few hours in the garden of the hotel and taking pictures of the peacocks and around 10:30 we left towards the coast, south and the leaning tower.
The road we took was mostly on toll highways – the directions in Google maps were very useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>