<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>canada on Miro&#39;s World</title>
    <link>https://miroadamy.com/tags/canada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in canada on Miro&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 22:57:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://miroadamy.com/tags/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rogers, iPhone and the dreaded kCFErrorDomainCFNetwork Error 302</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-08-23-rogers-iphone-and-the-dreaded-kcferrordomaincfnetwork-error-302/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 22:57:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-08-23-rogers-iphone-and-the-dreaded-kcferrordomaincfnetwork-error-302/</guid>
      <description>Many people recently (including myself) had experiences difficulties with Web access on the iPhone. Quite often the following error message pops up:
Usually repeating the web page access helps. Sometimes you have to try third time or wait few minutes.
This has nothing to do with signal strenght - as you can see, there are 4 bars and 3G is on. I saw it happen on Edge as well. Reseting the phone sometimes helps, but it is hard to say whether because of the reset or time delay .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DMCA for Canada ? Act now !</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-06-02-dmca-for-canada-act-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 23:33:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-06-02-dmca-for-canada-act-now/</guid>
      <description>I have got a letter from Online Rights Canada. I believe that what is about to hapen, may have pretty deep implications down the stream. Minimum thing I can do is try to help spreading the word.
Here is the message:
Dear Online Rights Canada Supporter,
We understand that the government will imminently introduce legislation to amend the Copyright Act - and it intends to push it through quickly. We at Online Rights Canada wanted to let you know what was ahead in the next few weeks, and what you can do to protect Canada from a new DMCA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rogers, Bell and Net neutrality</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-05-03-rogers-bell-and-net-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 20:09:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-05-03-rogers-bell-and-net-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>I do not blog on political issues, but this one is kind of different.
Couple of weeks ago I received a letter from my ISP provider (Rogers Cable), stating that days of unlimited downloads are over. More or less. Rogers capped the monthly transfer depending on your subscription plan, which in my case means maximum 95 GB / month for sum of upload and download.
They started to monitor the traffic in December and will start charging for the transfer exceeding the cap in June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroes Happened ... here</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-04-17-heroes-happened-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 09:50:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-04-17-heroes-happened-here/</guid>
      <description>Last week I attended one day event organized by Microsoft named Heroes Happens Here. It is series of introduction targeting new products: Windows Server 2008 (not out yet) SQL Server 2008 (not out yet) and Visual Studio 2008 (out and well).
I do not do much Microsoft development these days - my world is currently rather unevenly divided between Java (about 70 %), Web-ish technologies (XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, some Ruby) and OS-X (Objective C) which I am trying to squeeze in and get finally started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On White Stuff and Other Disasters</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-03-13-on-white-stuff-and-other-disasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 21:29:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-03-13-on-white-stuff-and-other-disasters/</guid>
      <description>Guess what are three most useful tools without which no proper Ottawa household can exist ? Snow shovel, snow pusher and car window ice scratcher. If the number was 4, the next would be snowblower. Up to yesterday, our family was in safe position being equipped with several shovels, four or five scratchers and one pusher.
Then disaster stroke: my son broke the pusher while moving away few cube meters of snow we removed from the roof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great way how to deal with telemarketers</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-10-08-great-way-how-to-deal-with-telemarketers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 22:39:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-10-08-great-way-how-to-deal-with-telemarketers/</guid>
      <description>and similar plague (for some reason they were pretty active last few days):
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=un_PjRXV5l8
I wish I could pull similar stunt - but I am not really a good actor and my accent would make it hard to believe. But it is hilarious anyway (video is a recording of phone call and contains text transcription ...). Enjoy.
Thanks to Peter M. for the link. I would link his blog or home page, if he had one :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game over, back to business</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-06-07-game-over-back-to-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 20:34:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-06-07-game-over-back-to-business/</guid>
      <description>The wild ride is over and the city gets back to normal. I wish we had won the Cup, but - Ducks were playing pretty good and found what worked on our team. Thanks, Alfie and the Sens - for all the great moments. You were fantastic. There will be another season in few months and another chance to bring the cup home.
On the positive side - it is good to have 2-3 more free evenings a week, now - when there is again nothing on the TV :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unify Tour 2007 and Open Source</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-04-19-unify-tour-2007-and-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 23:44:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-04-19-unify-tour-2007-and-open-source/</guid>
      <description>This week was full with attending the demos and workshops. On Tuesday, I spent half day on the Microsoft Unify Tour 2007. I planned to be there full day but an important business meeting made me change the plan. Fortunately, the sessions should be available recorded on the Web, so I will be able to check them later. The topic was bang-on - considering that we are in final phase of large project, using distributed network of SQL Server 2005 installations with replication and location was same as usual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sales as Con Art - or welcome to Direct Energy flat rate plan</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-28-sales-as-con-art-or-welcome-to-direct-energy-flat-rate-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 21:59:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-28-sales-as-con-art-or-welcome-to-direct-energy-flat-rate-plan/</guid>
      <description>During over 8 years living on this continent I&#39;ve developed reasonably thick skin in dealing with business calls, unsolicited mailings and other annoyances of aggressive selling. I was pretty sure nothing can make me really upset. Up until yesterday. Thanks to amazing capability of the Direct Energy sales force who does not take No for an answer.
But let&#39;s start from the beginning. About 3 weeks ago I started to get frequent calls from Direct Energy about their flat rate plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for a new day (continued)</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-13-ready-for-a-new-day-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2006 22:05:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-13-ready-for-a-new-day-continued/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned yesterday, my expectations regarding Office 2007 were fairly low. I am not a big fan of office application suites and for most of my editing I am using either on-line tools (like Google docs or Writeboard) or Open Office. True, neither of them has the smoothness and fine polish of Microsoft Office 2003, neither has all of it&#39;s features, but - let&#39;s face it - I barely use maybe 10-20% of Word or Excel capabilities anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for a new day - or Vista-Office-Exchange launch</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-12-ready-for-a-new-day-or-vista-office-exchange-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 23:56:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-12-ready-for-a-new-day-or-vista-office-exchange-launch/</guid>
      <description>Today was a big day in Ottawa Microsoft community. The Congress Centre was hosting large event - simultaneous launch of Windows Vista, Office 2007 and Exchange server 2007. Because I have almost registered about two months ago, I attended the event. The &#34;almost&#34; means that I tried to register right after receiving MSDN Flash email, but many people must have been faster - I was put on waiting list on two of the 3 tracks (Developers and IT Pros) and before I could even try to register for the third track (Business), everything crashed, Web site hang and I have never heard back from them, nor received any email.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>