<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on Miro&#39;s World</title>
    <link>https://miroadamy.com/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on Miro&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 11:22:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://miroadamy.com/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BOTD - Blog of the Day</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2019-12-05-silvias-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2019-12-05-silvias-blog/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s blog of the day is a special one. It does not deal with cloud, DevOps or distributed systems. The theme of the blog is travel, life of digital nomad and observations on life from a perspective of a smart young woman, working as Online English teacher and travelling a lot while doing so - https://bookandtravel.blog/
What makes this blog dear and interesting to me is that it&amp;rsquo;s author is my daughter Silvia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2018-09-15-road-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2018-09-15-road-trip/</guid>
      <description>I took 3 days off and decided to explore the North of Spain, namely Cantabria and Asturias.
It was awesome and beautiful. Asturias reminded me of Switzerland, with beautiful alpine style nature, great food, very friendly locals speaking language one can understand :-) (I kinda do understand certain versions of Schwyzzertütsch when spoken slowly - but it is a challenge).
Unlike Switzerland, it is not überexpensive.
Here are the pictures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas in Canada</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2017-01-26-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2017-01-26-canada/</guid>
      <description>We have visited Canada for the winter season.
It was very nice to see old friends and family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images from vacation are on Smugmug</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-09-13-images-from-vacation-are-on-smugmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 22:17:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-09-13-images-from-vacation-are-on-smugmug/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who asked: I started to put up some images from Europe 2007 trip on Smugmug. Small subset of course (total amount with NEFs is almost 20 GB).
I will upload more as I get to weeding them out :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back again</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-28-back-again-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 13:21:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-28-back-again-2/</guid>
      <description>After three amazing weeks, I am back again on-line - reading through emails and trying to sort out and process over 15 GB images. Shooting RAW has consequences :-).
Some of the see-worthy places and stories from the trip will start appearing here as the time permits to process my notes from the road. Stay tuned ...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe 2007 - 1</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-1/</guid>
      <description>Europe 2007 - 1: Switzerland, Lower Engadin The flight went pretty quickly. It was less than 7 hours, anyway. We crossed the night and the Atlantic in a short time and landed at 6 AM in rainy, wet Zurich.
The car I have retrieved from Europa car was Spanish Volkswagen make – Seat Leon. According the specification, it was a “medium size car”. And it maybe was, for European circumstances. For me it felt fairly small – our luggage did barely fit into the trunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe 2007 - 2</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-2/</guid>
      <description>Europe 2007 - 2: Südtirol and Verona Welcome to Italy: Verona After the breakfast, we took off from Scuol direction Martina, via brief drive through Austria to Italy. If I would not consult the map, I would barely noticed the border crossing, because there was no passport control on neither of the Switzerland-Austria or Austria-Italy border. You will not really notice that you have left Switzerland either, unless you notice the prices on gas stations being suddenly in Euro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe 2007 - 3</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-20-europe-2007-3/</guid>
      <description>Europe 2007 - 3: Pisa, Tirrenia and Firenze Pisa and Firenze After wonderful evening in Verona, the next day after a very good breakfast (they even had whole-wheat breads), we spend few hours in the garden of the hotel and taking pictures of the peacocks and around 10:30 we left towards the coast, south and the leaning tower.
The road we took was mostly on toll highways – the directions in Google maps were very useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On vacation</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-15-on-vacations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2007 17:13:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-08-15-on-vacations/</guid>
      <description>In case you were wondering why the blog went silent - I am touring Europe (Switzerland and Italy). Will post some stories after return ... and pictures on Smugmug - promise !
Greetings from Rome (just made it here tonight)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back again</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-10-13-back-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 23:28:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-10-13-back-again/</guid>
      <description>I have been back since Monday October 2nd late night, but until today, the backlog of things in both projects did not leave enough time to do any blogging. Not even any project-unrelated thinking - which is a prerequisite. Thanks to long weekend, I almost caught up with my backlog in both projects, so I can get back to the fun part of business such as Internet and blogs ...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking off</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-09-19-taking-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2006 14:19:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-09-19-taking-off/</guid>
      <description>In few hours I am taking off for a quick trip overseas, which very likely means that I will be quiet - at least as far as blogging goes. Not that the place I am heading to is not wired enough - actually, the broadband penetration is surprisingly high. The real reason is that I will be moving around a lot and meeting lot of people, so the blog must wait (yes, I am taking the Mac with me - what have you expected .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>