<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>startup-life on Miro&#39;s World</title>
    <link>https://miroadamy.com/categories/startup-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in startup-life on Miro&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 11:22:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://miroadamy.com/categories/startup-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Miro Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2012-02-15-miro-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2012-02-15-miro-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Miro Manifesto Original text of the memo, written in February 2012 and shared with limited audience, until it surfaced up as main them of the planning meeting in December 2012.
This is an attempt to come up with better answers to the following questions:
 what issues and challenges I see on our way ahead from the technology point of view and what needs to be done to address them where do I see my professional and personal career go over next 12 to 18 months and in long run how to best align those two streams  In the spirit of my latest “back to the basics” obsession, it was written in Markdown format and in Vi, copied and pasted into Google Doc, btw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here we go again</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2009-12-30-blog-reloade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 12:56:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2009-12-30-blog-reloade/</guid>
      <description>This is reloaded version of my previous blog - or continuation of the fork.
First thing to start is to explain why did I do something quite contra-productive as relocate the blog and loose all the audience - however small it could have been.
It would seem that I like restarts and things reloaded. I did pick a new country to become new home for me and my family (if emigration is not a restart, what else is ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s alive !</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2009-02-18-its-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 20:26:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2009-02-18-its-alive/</guid>
      <description>I was aching to blog about this since December 18th, when our system quietly and gently slipped into public visibility. Marked as Beta (thanks, Google for making this a legitimate way how to go live) it comfortably made it through Christmas shopping season into 2009.
Now when the site has been announced and mentioned few times in the media, I guess it&#39;s OK to mention it here too.
What is &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are hiring</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-08-26-we-are-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 10:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-08-26-we-are-hiring/</guid>
      <description>After everything-but-quiet summer, things got even busier and we need to add more great people to our teams.
At the moment we&#39;re looking for
* Junior Java developers
* Intermediate Java developers
* Intermediate .Net developers
* Senior .Net developers
* Junior Graphics/UI/Multimedia Designer
Sorry - no teleworking, you must be local to apply. If you feel like fitting in - or know somebody in Ottawa that would fit, email Miro at thinknostic dot com .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile development team member mantra</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-04-21-agile-development-team-member-mantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2008 00:24:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-04-21-agile-development-team-member-mantra/</guid>
      <description>Introducing code review and pair programming has often an impact on relationships in the team - especially when a critique needs to be delivered. It takes great degree of experience on both sides to communicate defects in the code for both the reviewer as well as for the code author to get something useful out of it.
I found this at http://www.finetix.com/blogs/finetixblogs.html which can be helpful (page is 404-ing now, but I luckily saved it in Google Docs way back) :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leopard in business environment - week 1</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-11-15-leopard-in-business-environment-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 23:11:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-11-15-leopard-in-business-environment-week-1/</guid>
      <description>I have already worked through full week solely on Mac and Leopard platform with excellent results. The productivity in using Java is actually higher, thanks to faster machine and Spaces allowing to have opened few Firefox windows with Spring documentation, terminals for Ant builds, Tomcat, Eclipse and Spype/Adium to keep in touch. Spaces is about as good as having multiple monitors - the ability of switching between both with mouse and keyboard fits well in my working habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On hardwood floors and software engineering</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-11-05-on-hardwood-floors-and-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 22:57:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-11-05-on-hardwood-floors-and-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>I am in the middle of a non-computer related project. Last week we have decided to get rid of carpeting in my home office and library and to put in the hardwood floor. My wife picked the wood and color, I picked the contractor, with my son&#39;s help we moved out the furniture and the renovation started. The most painful thing was shutting down and disconnecting all the computers and servers - only the lonely router is hanging on the wall and suffering the dust and noise of the power tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Like Netmeeting - only much better</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-10-03-like-netmeeting-only-much-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 03:10:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-10-03-like-netmeeting-only-much-better/</guid>
      <description>My current client is multi-national company, headquartered in Ottawa with offices in USA and Europe. With teams all over the globe, the conference calls and network meetings are part of the game. This usually means Microsoft Netmeeting to share the screen and teleconference bridge for voice. Netmeeting usually works quite OK - except when it does not - for no obvious reason :-).
Thanks to Yugma, there is now better alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh cup of Java</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-09-06-fresh-cup-of-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-09-06-fresh-cup-of-java/</guid>
      <description>Hi, all Java gurus inside and outside of Thinknostic - I have a very interesting problem. Imagine the following situation: we have three existing Java Web applications, written back in 2000/2001, based on open source libraries of that time: Struts 0.9/1.0 and JSP 1.x (no JSTL) with Tiles for Web layer, Apache Torque for ORM, early version of Quartz for job scheduling, Jasper Reports for PDF reports and Freemarker as template engine for email creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing broken ASP.NET development environment</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-05-03-fixing-broken-windows-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 22:18:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-05-03-fixing-broken-windows-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>I had again the not-so infrequent pleasure of setting up fresh copy of Windows development stack. We were moving few machines between projects and to make sure that no forgotten source files are left on the harddisk, we reformatted and reinstalled Windows from scratch. It is usually good idea anyway, because developers like to install strange tools and utilities and generally customize machines to their own taste, which tend to be unique and is seldom shared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four quadrants of uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-04-21-four-quadrants-of-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2007 22:54:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-04-21-four-quadrants-of-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>(a followup to discussion last week)

In every outsourced software project you have four large areas: your customer, the business vertical you are writing software for, your implementation team and the technology foundation or platform you are using.
Two of these areas are on &#34;internal&#34; side of your organization (team and technology), two of them are on external - your customer side (business domain and customer organization). Two are more micro level in the sense that they have strong human interaction aspect (customer and team) and two are more macrolevel and less personal (business domain and technology).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Myers-Briggs, Spaghetti Sauce and Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-02-15-on-myers-briggs-spaghetti-sauce-and-getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 23:33:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-02-15-on-myers-briggs-spaghetti-sauce-and-getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>Connie, our HR director came few weeks ago with interesting idea: give the team a chance to get better understanding of &#34;implementation details&#34; of their very own &#34;inner software&#34; - the personality type evaluation using Myers-Briggs approach. Connie holds certification for this type of classification.
The classification in a nutshell, assigns to everybody four letters, one from each pair: E or I, N or S, T or F, J or P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back on 2006</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-01-01-looking-back-on-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 21:46:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-01-01-looking-back-on-2006/</guid>
      <description>The 2006 was truly amazing year. We have accomplished so much - we have created the West end development centre, brought in and started several projects, completed phase 1 of employee conversion, started benefits program, ESOP program, redefined the company visual presence, grew the business and the company size considerably and created foundation for future growth.
Most important achievemnt is the fun factor - I am again looking forward to go to work - and again since the Montage days the synergy is coming back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Party time</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-15-party-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 23:55:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-15-party-time/</guid>
      <description>It is this time of year - Christmas parties. It looks like the number of parties we go to every year increases - did not figure out yet which function it is, let&#39;s hope it is not exponential. This year, the number was four. First was traditional Christmas party at Peter&#39;s place. Second one - which I unfortunately missed - was a gettogether of Montage/Allstream alumni. I was sick and in bed - sorry I missed this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki&#39;s are everywhere ...</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-11-21-wikis-are-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2006 21:05:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-11-21-wikis-are-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>Since the beginning of the biometric security project, we are using an excellent enterprise-level Wiki Confluence as knowledge repository and main team communication tool. I was not sure at the beginning, how will the Wiki approach work for all the people on the team, mostly because once before I already tried it and had not much success of introducing the idea. It was few years ago and the Wiki engine I used were nowhere in the same league as Confluence, but main problem at that time was probably the users&#39; mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moved in ...</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-09-14-moved-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2006 01:08:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-09-14-moved-in/</guid>
      <description>I have been pretty quiet in last few days. The reason why was hinted here - we have finally a space. The project started on Monday and we were running around like crazy since Sunday. Started with moving in looots of boxes - 9 workstations, each with two 19&#34; LCD monitors plus three servers, network gears, cables etc - three full cars. Then came the unpacking and setting up, which took much longer time that I would ever have expected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>