<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ottawa on Miro&#39;s World</title>
    <link>https://miroadamy.com/tags/ottawa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ottawa on Miro&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 11:22:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://miroadamy.com/tags/ottawa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit in Canada</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2019-05-25-ottawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 11:22:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2019-05-25-ottawa/</guid>
      <description>I did quick 2 week visit to Canada.
I spent some time with our son and daughter-in-law, visited many dear friends and places in the city and nature, worked for couple of days in the office and met new colleagues and even met current my boss for the first time in 3D. I must say, he is taller than in Zoom :-D
I also visited our ex-cat with her new human servants and as expected, Lucy duly ignored me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ByMUG meeting - August</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-08-05-bymug-meeting-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 23:30:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-08-05-bymug-meeting-august/</guid>
      <description>This Sunday, as every first Sunday in month we had regular Bytown Mac User Group meeting at usual place - Patty Bolands Pub at the Market. It was great meeting because we had many newcomers - both to the group as well as to the platform, including very fresh Mac switch - a happy owner of 24 hours old Macbook Pro.
The presentations were very suited for the audience of newcomers, especially Katheryne&#39;s demo on customizing the Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroes Happened ... here</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-04-17-heroes-happened-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 09:50:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-04-17-heroes-happened-here/</guid>
      <description>Last week I attended one day event organized by Microsoft named Heroes Happens Here. It is series of introduction targeting new products: Windows Server 2008 (not out yet) SQL Server 2008 (not out yet) and Visual Studio 2008 (out and well).
I do not do much Microsoft development these days - my world is currently rather unevenly divided between Java (about 70 %), Web-ish technologies (XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, some Ruby) and OS-X (Objective C) which I am trying to squeeze in and get finally started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On White Stuff and Other Disasters</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-03-13-on-white-stuff-and-other-disasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 21:29:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2008-03-13-on-white-stuff-and-other-disasters/</guid>
      <description>Guess what are three most useful tools without which no proper Ottawa household can exist ? Snow shovel, snow pusher and car window ice scratcher. If the number was 4, the next would be snowblower. Up to yesterday, our family was in safe position being equipped with several shovels, four or five scratchers and one pusher.
Then disaster stroke: my son broke the pusher while moving away few cube meters of snow we removed from the roof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game over, back to business</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-06-07-game-over-back-to-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 20:34:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-06-07-game-over-back-to-business/</guid>
      <description>The wild ride is over and the city gets back to normal. I wish we had won the Cup, but - Ducks were playing pretty good and found what worked on our team. Thanks, Alfie and the Sens - for all the great moments. You were fantastic. There will be another season in few months and another chance to bring the cup home.
On the positive side - it is good to have 2-3 more free evenings a week, now - when there is again nothing on the TV :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ottawa Mac User&#39;s group meeting</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-03-04-ottawa-mac-users-group-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 17:02:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2007-03-04-ottawa-mac-users-group-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to exploring the Google calendar (when playing with public calendars related to Ottawa) I found the Ottawa Mac User group&#39;s calendar and discovered that
a) they exist
b) they hold monthly meetings in nice Irish pub at the Market 
The group is actually named Bytown Mac User&#39;s group, for the reasons explained on the Web site or here.
So I decided to go there. I thought - what the heck, worst thing that can happen that I will have a glass of Guinness at the pub I never visited before, which is not a bad thing at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for a new day (continued)</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-13-ready-for-a-new-day-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2006 22:05:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-13-ready-for-a-new-day-continued/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned yesterday, my expectations regarding Office 2007 were fairly low. I am not a big fan of office application suites and for most of my editing I am using either on-line tools (like Google docs or Writeboard) or Open Office. True, neither of them has the smoothness and fine polish of Microsoft Office 2003, neither has all of it&#39;s features, but - let&#39;s face it - I barely use maybe 10-20% of Word or Excel capabilities anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready for a new day - or Vista-Office-Exchange launch</title>
      <link>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-12-ready-for-a-new-day-or-vista-office-exchange-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 23:56:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miroadamy.com/posts/2006-12-12-ready-for-a-new-day-or-vista-office-exchange-launch/</guid>
      <description>Today was a big day in Ottawa Microsoft community. The Congress Centre was hosting large event - simultaneous launch of Windows Vista, Office 2007 and Exchange server 2007. Because I have almost registered about two months ago, I attended the event. The &#34;almost&#34; means that I tried to register right after receiving MSDN Flash email, but many people must have been faster - I was put on waiting list on two of the 3 tracks (Developers and IT Pros) and before I could even try to register for the third track (Business), everything crashed, Web site hang and I have never heard back from them, nor received any email.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>